Finding Aid for Dept. of Biology (University of Michigan) Records 1879-[ongoing]
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
Dept. of Biology (University of Michigan) Records 1879-[ongoing]
University of Michigan. Dept. of Biology.
20 linear feet
Department of Biology (established 1986) of the University of Michigan, and of its predecessor unit, the Division of Biological Sciences, and the departments (Botany and Zoology) that comprised the division. Records include minutes, correspondence, course materials, and various subject files.
861034 Bimu C26 2
Bentley Historical Library University of Michigan
The record group was donated by the Department of Biology (Donor No. 7328 ).
The records are open for research with the exception of search files and various personnel and student files. Individual folders (arranged by year) in the Promotions series (boxes 18-20) are closed for thirty years from date of creation. The contents lists contains notations for all other folders which have been closed and removed to box 20 because their contents relate to student/personnel confidential matters.
The beginnings of the Department of Biology can be traced to 1875, when separate lectures in biology evolved from the Departments of Botany and Zoology. Instruction in botany and zoology at the University of Michigan began in the 1840s, several years after the appointment of the university's first professor of botany and zoology in 1838. Botany and zoology were initially taught by the same professors, but separate departments were established in 1879. In order to promote closer communication between members of the biology faculty and the administration of the University, an informal group called the Division of the Biological Sciences was formed in 1948. The division helped to coordinate research and other activities of related departments, schools, and colleges. In 1975, the Regents authorized the formal creation of the Division of Biological Sciences, as an administrative unit within the College of Literature, Sciences, and the Arts. The new division was responsible for the coordination of curricula and research in the various disciplines of the biological sciences. On July 1, 1986, the Division of Biological Sciences became the Department of Biology.
The Department of Biology records, 1879-19992, measure 5 linear feet and include minutes, correspondence, course materials, and various subject files. The records are organized into ten series: Departmental and Divisional Records, Printed Material, Divisional Administration, Staff, Academics, Students, Logistics, Biological Units, Outside Relations, and Promotions.
Subjects:
University of Michigan. Dept. of Botany.; University of Michigan. Dept. of Zoology.; University of Michigan. Matthaei Botanical Gardens.; University of Michigan. Great Lakes Research Division.; University of Michigan. Institute of Human Biology.; University of Michigan. Laboratory of Vertebrate Biology.; University of Michigan. Biological Station.; University of Michigan--Students.; Minority college students--Michigan--Ann Arbor.
- Departmental and Divisional Records
  The departmental and divisional records are divided into three subseries: the Division of Biological Sciences, the Botany Department, and the Zoology Department. Material within each of these subseries is arranged alphabetically by topic or committee name and then chronologically. Records of Division of Biological Sciences that existed from 1948 to 1975, and of its successor of the same name, are filed in the same series but can be distinguished by date. The records consist primarily of minutes of faculty and committee meetings, correspondence, reports, newsletters, course outlines, and announcements. Of particular note are the minutes of faculty meetings of the Botany and Zoology Departments, which run from the 1910s to 1975, with some gaps, and the Zoology Department Executive Committee minutes, which date from 1934 to 1975.
  In addition to the departmental and divisional records, there are several folders of miscellaneous material relating to the Biological Stations, Botanical Gardens, the Great Lakes Research Institute, the Laboratory of Vertebrate Biology, and the Natural Science Study Committee. These folders are filed at the end of the collection under the heading "Miscellaneous."
  - Biological Sciences, Division of
    - Curriculum Committee
      - 1975-1976 (Box 1)
      - 1976-1977 (Box 1)
      - 1977-1982 (Box 1)
    - Executive Committee: Minutes
      - June-December, 1975 (Box 1)
      - January-June, 1976 (Box 1)
      - 1976-1977 (Box 1)
      - 1977-1978 (Box 1)
      - 1978-1979 (Box 1)
      - 1979-1980 (Box 1)
      - 1980-1981 (Box 1)
      - 1981-1982 (Box 1)
      - 1982-1983 (Box 1)
    - General Committee: Minutes 1958-1965 (Box 1)
    - Gnats Eye Gnus (newsletter)
      - 1977-1979 (Box 1)
      - 1979-1981 (Box 1)
      - 1982-1983 (Box 1)
    - Graduate Admissions 1975-1982 (Box 1)
    - Graduate Affairs Committee 1977, 1985 (Box 1)
    - Research, Committee on: "The Present Status of Research" March, 1955 (Box 1)
    - Seminars: Announcements 1971-1984, 3 folders (Box 2)
    - Summer Biological Symposium: Programs 1950-1965 (Box 2)
  - Botany, Department of
    - Communications with Regents and President 1879, 1894-1909/1910 (Box 2)
    - Correspondence 1881-1910 (Box 2)
    - Course Notes and Examinations 1904-1910 (Box 2)
    - Curriculum Committee 1971-1974 (Box 2)
    - Examination Record 1890-1907 (Box 2)
    - Examinations 1894-1898 (Box 2)
    - Examinations and Class Lists 1896-1902, 1907 (Box 2)
    - Executive Committee: Minutes
      - 1963-1967 (Box 2)
      - 1968-1972 (Box 2)
    - Graduate Study (Box 2)
    - Plan for Botanical Department and Botanical Garden 1912-1913 (Box 2)
    - Requests to the Auditing Board 1893-1909 (Box 2)
    - Staff Meeting: Minutes
      - 1914-1924 (Box 2)
      - 1925-1932 (Box 2)
      - 1933-1937 (Box 2)
      - 1938-1943 (Box 2)
      - 1944-1947 (Box 2)
      - 1948-1953 (Box 2)
      - 1954-May 1963 (Box 2)
      - 1937-1963 Summary Index (Box 2)
      - September 1963-1965 (Box 2)
      - 1966-1968 (Box 2)
      - 1969-1972 (Box 3)
  - Zoology, Department of
    - Constitution and Bylaws 1925 (Box 3)
    - Construction and Renovation Plans
      - 1931-1966 (Box 3)
      - 1967-1972 (Box 3)
    - Correspondence with Deans
      - Haber, William 1964-1968 (Box 3)
      - Hayes, William 1967-1970 (Box 3)
      - Rhodes, Frank 1971-1974 (Box 3)
      - Sussman, Alfred 1968-1971 (Box 3)
      - Thuma, Burton 1952-1963 (Box 3)
    - Course Expenditures 1963-1973 (Box 3)
    - Course Outlines: Zoology-Botany 1969-1972 (Box 3)
    - Curriculum Committee
      - 1971-1972 (Box 3)
      - 1973-1974 (Box 3)
    - Examinations
      - Area and Diagnostic 1972-1975 (Box 3)
      - Graduate 1953-1973 (Box 3)
    - Executive Committee: Minutes
      - December 1934-June 1937 (Box 3)
      - September 1937-June 1939 (Box 3)
      - September 1939-June 1944 (Box 3)
      - August 1944-June 1946 (Box 3)
      - September 1946-June 1949 (Box 3)
      - February 1950-June 1954 (Box 4)
      - September 1954-June 1956 (Box 4)
      - September 1956-June 1957 (Box 4)
      - September 1957-December 1959 (Box 4)
      - 1960-1961 (Box 4)
      - 1962-1963 (Box 4)
      - 1964-April 1965 (Box 4)
      - September 1965-June 1966 (Box 4)
      - July 1966-June 1976 (Box 4)
      - September 1967-May 1968 (Box 4)
      - August 1968, June 1970 (Box 4)
      - September 1970-June 1971 (Box 4)
      - September 1971-June 1972 (Box 4)
      - September 1972-June 1973 (Box 4)
      - September 1973-June 1974 (Box 4)
      - September 1974-May 1975 (Box 5)
    - Faculty Meeting Minutes
      - 1912-1922 (Box 5)
      - 1925-1927 (Box 5)
      - 1935-1949 (Box 5)
      - 1950-1966 (Box 5)
      - 1967-1975 (Box 5)
    - Faculty Workload: Reports 1957, 1969-1974 (Box 5)
    - Graduate Admissions 1972-1974 (Box 5)
    - Graduate Affairs Committee
      - 1927-1950 (Box 5)
      - 1951-1985 (Box 5)
    - Laboratory of Mouse Genetics 1957-1959 (Box 5)
    - Library Committee Allocations 1934-1948 (Box 5)
    - Museum of Zoology Seminars: Announcements 1977-1982 (Box 5)
    - Review of Department (Report of Visiting Panel) 1966 (Box 5)
    - Seminars: Announcements 1971-1972 (Box 5)
    - Staff Negotiations with Deans 1965-1972 (Box 5)
    - Zoological Journal Club 1913-1927 (Box 5)
  - Miscellaneous
    - Biological Stations 1962-1967 (Box 5)
    - Black Student Recruitment 1970-1971 (Box 5)
    - Botanical Gardens 1957-1964 (Box 5)
    - Great Lakes Research Institute 1945-1959 (Box 5)
    - Institute of Human Biology and Laboratory of Vertebrate
      - Biology 1947-1957 (Box 5)
    - Natural Science Study Committee 1957-1959 (Box 5)
- Printed Material
  - Department of Biology
    - Announcement of courses 1994-1995 (Box 6)
    - Brochures Undated, 1989 (Box 6)
    - Bulletins
      - Graduate Studies in Biology
        - circa 1992 (Box 6)
    - Newsletters
      - Gnat's Eye Gnus
        - 1989-1990 (Box 6)
        - 1990-1991 (Box 6)
        - 1991-1992 (Box 6)
  - Department of Botany
    - Histories circa 1953 (Box 6)
    - Newsletter
      - U-M Botany Times
        - 1990- (Box 6)
- Divisional Administration
  The Divisional Administration series (3.2 linear feet) is arranged alphabetically by subject and contains records which relate to the internal activities of the Department of Biology. The records include meeting minutes, committee files, and internal and external review materials. There is also General Correspondence, primarily to and from the chairman. It is in chronological order in box 9; the correspondence in box 20 arrived unfoldered and in no order and has only been foldered.
  - College of Literature, Science and the Arts
    - Chairmen and Directors Meeting Minutes
      - 1974-1975 (Box 7)
      - 1976-1977 (Box 7)
      - 1978-1979 (Box 7)
      - 1980-1981 (Box 7)
      - 1982-1983 (Box 7)
    - Committee on Curriculum 1974-1976 (Box 7)
    - College Curriculum Committee
      - 1977-1978 (Box 7)
      - 1978-1979 (Box 7)
      - 1979-1980 (Box 7)
      - 1980-1981 (Box 7)
      - 1982-1983 (Box 7)
      - 1983-1984 (Box 7)
      - 1984-1985 (Box 7)
  - Committee on Formulation of the Rules of
    - Governance 1974-1975 (Box 7)
  - Correspondence
    - Position Candidates
      - P. Dunsmuir 1982-1983 (Box 7)
      - P. William Fink 1982-1983 (Box 7)
      - Wayne Frasch 1982-1983 (Box 7)
  - Executive Committee Minutes
    - Zoology
      - 1971-1972 (Box 7)
      - 1973 (Box 7)
      - 1973-1974 (Box 7)
      - 1974-1975, 2 folders (Box 7)
    - Division of Biological Sciences
      - 1975-1976, 3 folders
        - folders 1-2 (Box 7)
        - folder 3 (Box 8)
      - 1976-1977, 3 folders (Box 8)
      - 1977-1978, 4 folders (Box 8)
      - 1978-1979, 3 folders (Box 8)
      - 1979-1980, 6 folders
        - folders 1-3 (Box 8)
        - folders 4-6 (Box 9)
      - 1980-1981, 2 folders (Box 9)
      - 1981-1982, 2 folders (Box 9)
      - 1992-1998 (Box 9)
        (scattered dates)
  - External Review
    - 1979-1980 (Box 9)
    - 1980-1981 (Box 9)
    - 1982-1983 (Box 9)
  - General Correspondence
    (mostly from/to chairman)
    - Undated, 7 folders (Box 9)
    - October 1968-June 1974 (Box 9)
    - July 1974-December 1974 (Box 9)
    - January 1975-April 1975 (Box 9)
    - May 1975-June 1975 (Box 9)
    - July 1975-September 1975 (Box 10)
    - October 1975-November 1975 (Box 10)
    - December 1975-January 1976 (Box 10)
    - February 1976-April 1976 (Box 10)
    - May 1976-June 1976 (Box 10)
    - July 1976-December 1976 (Box 10)
    - January 1977-June 1977 (Box 10)
    - July 1977-June 1978 (Box 10)
    - July 1978-June 1979 (Box 10)
    - July 1979-June 1980 (Box 10)
    - July 1980-June 1981 (Box 10)
    - July 1981-December 1981 (Box 10)
    - January 1982-June 1982 (Box 10)
    - July 1982-June 1983 (Box 10)
    - July 1983-March 1984 (Box 10)
    - July 1984-June 1989 (Box 10)
  - Graduate Examination Committee Records 1953-1970, 1 notebook (Box 11)
  - Herbarium
    - "An Informational Report for the Committees Reviewing the Herbarium in Fall 1979" (Box 11)
  - Internal and External Reviews 1979 (Box 11)
  - LS&A Deanship Search
    - 1975 (Box 20)
    - 1980-1981 (Box 20)
  - Malacology Search 1984-1985 (Box 11)
  - Martin Complaint 1977-1978 (Box 20)
  - Material for Divisional Brochure 1979-1980 (Box 11)
  - Mitchell, J. Grievance Hearing 1980-1981 (Box 20)
  - Position Request
    - 1982-1983 (Box 11)
    - 1983-1984 (Box 11)
    - 1984-1985 (Box 11)
  - Reorganization of Biology 1974-1975 (Box 11)
  - Rules of Governance 1983-1984 (Box 11)
  - Sabbatical Leave Schedule
    - 1982-1983 (Box 11)
    - 1983-1984 (Box 11)
    - 1984-1985 (Box 11)
  - Safety Policy for Laboratory Students 1978-1979 (Box 11)
  - Staffing/Retirement Schedule 1984-1985 (Box 11)
  - Travel Policies
    - 1983-1984 (Box 11)
    - 1984-1985 (Box 11)
  - University General Counsel 1982-1983 (Box 11)
- Staff
  The Staff series (2.5 linear feet) is arranged alphabetically by subject. It contains materials on hiring policies and searches for both academic and non-academic positions.
  - Academic Staffing
    - 1975-1976, 2 folders (Box 11)
    - 1976-1977, 2 folders (Box 11)
    - 1977 (Box 11)
    - 1977-1978, 2 folders (Box 11)
    - 1978-1979 (Box 11)
    - 1979-1980, 2 folders (Box 12)
    - 1980-1981, 2 folders (Box 12)
    - 1981-1982 (Box 12)
    - 1982-1983 (Box 12)
  - Affirmative Action
    - 1975 (Box 12)
    - 1976-1977 (Box 12)
    - 1977-1978 (Box 12)
    - 1978-1979 (Box 12)
    - 1979-1980 (Box 12)
    - 1980-1981 (Box 12)
    - 1981-1982 (Box 12)
  - Alumni Newsletter 1980 (Box 12)
  - Amphibian Center 1979-1980 (Box 12)
  - Amphibian Facility 1979 (Box 12)
  - Awards Committee
    - 1979-1980 (Box 12)
    - 1980-1981 (Box 12)
    - 1981-1982 (Box 12)
  - Biological Sciences Faculty Minutes 1975-1977 (Box 12)
  - Carlson, Bruce 1978-1979 (Box 12)
  - Curriculum Committee 1976-1977 (Box 12)
  - Committee on Promotions and Staff Development 1974-1976 (Box 12)
  - Culture Technician Job 1980-1981 (Box 12)
  - Faculty Awards Committee
    - 1980-1981 (Box 12)
    - 1983-1984 (Box 12)
    - 1984-1985 (Box 12)
  - Faculty Personnel Records 1979 (Box 12)
  - Graduate Programs 1975-1976 (Box 12)
  - Interest Groups 1974-1975 (Box 12)
  - Junior Fellow Program
    - 1978-1979 (Box 12)
    - 1984-1985 (Box 12)
  - Literature, Science and the Arts, College of, Dean Candidates, 1975-76 (Box 12)
  - Non-Academic Staff--Evaluation Summaries
    - 1974-1976 (Box 13)
    - 1978-1979 (Box 13)
    - 1979-1980 (Box 13)
    - 1980-1981 (Box 13)
    - 1984-1985 (Box 13)
  - Primary Research Staff--Wes Brown, 1980-81 (Box 13)
  - Rules of Governance, 1975-77 (Box 13)
  - Salary Program
    - 1980-1981 (Box 13)
    - 1983-1984 (Box 13)
    - 1984-1985 (Box 13)
  - Searches
    [Closed]
    - Biophysics
      - 1976-1977 (Box 20)
      - 1978-1979 (Box 20)
    - Center for Human Growth and Development (CHGD), Directorship 1979-1980 (Box 20)
    - Curator of Insects 1978-1979 (Box 20)
    - Developmental Biology 1979-1980 (Box 20)
    - Ecology
      - Junior 1977-1978, 2 folders (Box 20)
      - Senior
        - 1975-1976 (Box 20)
        - 1977-1978 (Box 20)
    - Endocrinology Search 1977 (Box 20)
    - Limnology 1977-1978 (Box 20)
    - Malacology Search, 1976-77 (Box 20)
    - Mammalogist, 1978-79 (Box 20)
    - Microbiology 1978-1979 (Box 20)
    - Molecular Genetics 1977-1978 (Box 20)
    - Plant Molecular Biologist 1981 (Box 20)
  - Space Policy, 1984-85 (Box 13)
  - Subunit Affiliations 1975 (Box 13)
  - Temporary Lecturer Positions
    - 1982-1983 (Box 13)
    - 1984-1985 (Box 13)
  - Term II 1981 Lecturer Applications, 1980-81 (Box 13)
  - University Senate, 1978-79 (Box 13)
  - Visiting Professorships, 1984-85 (Box 13)
- Academics
  The Academics series (1.5 linear feet) is arranged alphabetically by subject. The series includes records on curriculum and program development.
  - Cellular & Molecular Biology Curriculum
    - 1982-1983 (Box 13)
    - 1983-1984 (Box 13)
  - Curriculum Committee, Division of Biological Science
    - 1975-1976 (Box 13)
    - 1977-1979 (Box 13)
    - 1979-1980 (Box 13)
    - 1980-1981 (Box 13)
    - 1982-1983 (Box 13)
    - 1983-1984 (Box 13)
    - 1984-1985 (Box 13)
  - Developmental Biology Program
    - 1982-1983 (Box 13)
    - 1983-1984 (Box 13)
  - Ecology Curriculum
    - 1983-1984 (Box 13)
    - 1984-1985 (Box 13)
  - English Composition Board
    - 1978-1979 (Box 13)
    - 1979-1980 (Box 13)
    - 1980-1981 (Box 13)
    - 1983-1984 (Box 13)
    - 1984-1985 (Box 13)
  - Gerontology Course
    - 1979 (Box 13)
    - 1980 (Box 13)
  - Grade Appeals Process
    - 1975-1976 (Box 20)
    - 1977-1978 (Box 20)
    - 1978-1979 (Box 20)
    - 1979-1980 (Box 20)
    - 1980-1981 (Box 20)
    - 1981-1982 (Box 20)
  - Honors Program circa 1980-1988 (Box 14)
  - Introductory Course Offerings
    - 1975-1976, 2 folders (Box 14)
    - 1978-1979 (Box 14)
    - 1983-1984 (Box 14)
    - 1984-1985 (Box 14)
  - Junior/Senior Writing Program 1980-1982 (Box 14)
  - Microbiology 1982-1983 (Box 14)
  - Molecular Genetics Program Center
    - 1982-1983 (Box 14)
    - 1983-1984 (Box 14)
  - Natural Science Library
    - 1980-1981 (Box 14)
    - 1981-1982 (Box 14)
    - 1983-1984 (Box 14)
  - Plant Biology Curriculum
    - 1982-1983 (Box 14)
    - 1983-1984 (Box 14)
    - 1984-1985 (Box 14)
  - Plant Physiology 1982-1983 (Box 14)
  - Program Evaluation
    - Botany 1975-1976 (Box 14)
    - Zoology 1975-1976 (Box 14)
  - Seminar Committee
    - 1975-1976 (Box 14)
    - 1977-1978 (Box 14)
    - 1978-1979 (Box 14)
    - 1979-1980 (Box 14)
    - 1980-1981 (Box 14)
    - 1981-1982 (Box 14)
    - 1984-1985 (Box 14)
  - Speech and Hearing 1977-1978 (Box 14)
  - Thurnau Committee
    - 1981-1982, 2 folders (Box 14)
    - 1982-1983 (Box 14)
  - Wahlgreen Chair 1980-1981 (Box 14)
  - Women Seminar Speakers 1975-1976 (Box 14)
  - Zoology Curriculum 1983-1984 (Box 14)
- Students
  The Students series (.75 linear feet) is arranged alphabetically by subject and is almost exclusively concerned with graduate students and graduate education. The series includes graduate committee minutes, M.S./M.A. committee minutes, and files on graduate student support.
  - Botany Graduate Affairs Committee
    - 1979-1980 (Box 14)
  - Fellowships and Scholarships 1982-1983 (Box 14)
  - Graduate Affairs Committee
    - 1975-1976, 3 folders (Box 15)
    - 1977-1978 (Box 15)
    - 1978-1979 (Box 15)
    - 1979-1980 (Box 15)
    - 1980-1981 (Box 15)
    - 1981-1982 (Box 15)
  - Graduate Student Support
    - 1975-1976 (Box 15)
    - 1977-1978 (Box 15)
    - 1979-1980 (Box 15)
    - 1980-1981 (Box 15)
  - M.S./M.A. Committee
    - 1978-1979 (Box 15)
    - 1979-1980 (Box 15)
    - 1980-1981 (Box 15)
    - 1981-1982 (Box 15)
    - 1982-1983 (Box 15)
    - 1983-1984 (Box 15)
    - 1984-1985 (Box 15)
  - Masters Program Evaluation Committee, 1978-79 (Box 15)
  - Minority Recruitment 1984-1985 (Box 15)
  - Ph.D. Admissions and Counsel 1983-1984 (Box 15)
  - Teacher Preparation 1982-1983 (Box 15)
  - Undergraduate Programs
    - 1982-1983 (Box 15)
    - 1984-1985 (Box 15)
- Logistics
  The Logistics series (1 linear foot) is arranged alphabetically by subject and contains records pertaining to maintenance of buildings and equipment. The records include files on various renovation projects.
  - Computerization 1983-1984 (Box 15)
  - Electron Microscope Administration
    - 1980-1981 (Box 15)
    - 1983-1984 (Box 15)
    - 1984-1985 (Box 15)
  - General Science Renovation Committee
    - 1977-1978 (Box 15)
    - 1979-1980 (Box 15)
  - Library Committee
    - 1978-1979 (Box 15)
    - 1980-1981 (Box 15)
    - 1983-1984 (Box 15)
  - C. C. Little Building Renovations
    - 1975-1976 (Box 15)
    - 1983-1984 (Box 15)
  - Museum of Zoology
    - 1974-1976 (Box 15)
    - 1979-1980 (Box 15)
    - 1984-1985 (Box 15)
  - Natural Science Renovation Committee
    - 1977-1978 (Box 15)
    - 1978-1979 (Box 15)
    - 1979-1980 (Box 16)
    - 1980-1981 (Box 16)
    - 1981-1982 (Box 16)
    - 1982-1983 (Box 16)
    - 1983-1984 (Box 16)
    - 1984-1985 (Box 16)
  - Space Committee
    - 1971-1975 (Box 16)
    - 1977-1978 (Box 16)
    - 1980-1981 (Box 16)
    - 1981-1982 (Box 16)
    - 1982-1983 (Box 16)
- Biological Units
  The Biological Units series (.75 linear feet) is arranged alphabetically by subject and contains the records of the various units maintained by the department including the Amphibian Center, Biological Station, Botanical Gardens, Herbarium, the Mouse Genetics Center and the Museum of Zoology.
  - Amphibian Center
    - 1975-1976 (Box 16)
    - 1977-1978 (Box 16)
    - 1978-1979 (Box 16)
    - 1980-1981 (Box 16)
    - 1981-1982 (Box 16)
  - Biological Station
    - 1975-1976 (Box 16)
    - 1977-1978 (Box 16)
    - 1978-1979 (Box 16)
    - 1979-1980 (Box 16)
    - 1981-1982 (Box 16)
    - 1982-1983 (Box 16)
    - 1983-1984 (Box 16)
    - 1984-1985 (Box 16)
  - Biomedical Research
    - 1977-1978 (Box 16)
    - 1978-1979 (Box 16)
    - 1980-1981 (Box 16)
    - 1983-1984 (Box 16)
  - Botanical Gardens
    - 1978-1979 (Box 16)
    - 1980-1981 (Box 16)
    - 1983-1984 (Box 16)
    - 1984-1985 (Box 16)
  - Botany Department
    - 1979-1980 (Box 16)
    - 1981-1982 (Box 16)
  - Cellular and Molecular Biology
    - 1980-1981 (Box 16)
    - 1981-1982 (Box 16)
  - Cellular and Molecular Genetics
    - 1975-1976 (Box 16)
    - 1978-1979 (Box 16)
  - Ecology and Evolutionary Biology
    - 1975 (Box 16)
    - 1979-1980 (Box 16)
    - 1981-1982 (Box 16)
  - Evolution and Human Biology 1982-1983 (Box 16)
  - Experimental Biology
    - 1975-1976 (Box 16)
    - 1979-1980 (Box 16)
  - Gerontology Course 1980-1981 (Box 16)
  - Herbarium
    - 1975-1976 (Box 16)
    - 1977-1978 (Box 16)
    - 1979-1980 (Box 16)
    - 1980-1981 (Box 16)
    - 1984-1985 (Box 16)
  - Mouse Genetics Center 1977-1978 (Box 17)
  - Museum of Zoology
    - 1977-1978 (Box 17)
    - 1978-1979 (Box 17)
    - 1979-1980 (Box 17)
    - 1980-1981 (Box 17)
    - 1983-1984 (Box 17)
  - Zoology Department 1981-1982 (Box 17)
- Outside Relations
  The Outside Relations series (.75 linear feet) is arranged alphabetically by subject and documents the department's relationship to other units in the University of Michigan. The series includes records pertaining to the Great Lakes Research Division and the Institute of Science and Technology, and materials from Chairman Dawson's trip with President Harold Shapiro to China in 1981.
  - Center for Human Growth and Development 1978-1979 (Box 17)
  - China Visit
    - 1980-1981 (Box 17)
    - 1981 (Box 17)
    - 1981-1982 (Box 17)
  - Great Lakes Research Division
    - 1977-1978 (Box 17)
    - 1978-1979 (Box 17)
    - 1979-1980 (Box 17)
    - 1980-1981 (Box 17)
    - 1982-1983 (Box 17)
    - 1983-1984 (Box 17)
    - 1984-1985 (Box 17)
  - Institute of Gerontology
    - 1983-1984 (Box 17)
    - 1984-1985 (Box 17)
  - Institute of Science and Technology (IST Executive Committee)
    - 1977-1978 (Box 17)
    - 1978-1979 (Box 17)
    - 1979-1980 (Box 17)
    - 1980-1981 (Box 17)
    - 1981-1982 (Box 17)
    - 1982-1983 (Box 17)
    - 1983-1984 (Box 17)
    - 1984-1985 (Box 17)
  - Neuroscience 1983-1984 (Box 17)
  - Relations with Other School/Colleges (primarily University of Michigan)
    - General
      - 1977-1978 (Box 17)
      - 1978-1979 (Box 17)
      - 1979-1980 (Box 17)
      - 1983-1984 (Box 17)
    - School of Education 1984-1985 (Box 17)
- Promotions 1960-1985
  The Promotions series (2.5 linear feet) is comprised of files, arranged chronologically, on promotion decisions. The Promotions files are closed for thirty years from date of creation.
  - General
    - 1960 (Box 18)
    - 1961 (Box 18)
    - 1962 (Box 18)
    - 1963 (Box 18)